♪The Upper Three hold the seals♪
♪A valiant general, an opera star, and a ruthless cripple♪
♪The Middle Three stir the clouds♪
♪A fiend, a wandering hero, and a master of the blade♪
♪The Lower Three deal in gold♪
♪A beauty, a seer, and a scholar♪
♪The Upper, Middle, and Lower Three♪
♪Represent the nine houses of old Changsha♪
♪Together, they are known♪
♪As the Mystic Nine♪
[Mystic Nine]
[Adapted from the novel of Kennedy Xu]
[Episode 5]
[This story is purely fictional]
How many times have you whistled now?
Are you sure it works?
Do you know why we call him Xiaoyu?
Master Zhang calls him Xiaoyu
because his Wedge Formation is as sharp as a blade
and his Fish-scale Formation is as tough as a turtle.
I don't care what he is.
We still can't save the victim.
I should do it myself.
Let me finish.
Know this.
- When Master Zhang was investigating the sea mine smuggling...
- Tiezui!
Master Zhang.
Master Zhang, what's wrong?
I want you
to tell me everything
that has happened since we entered
the Otherworld Tower.
Why are you hiding here?
What happened?
I saw a palanquin just now.
Why are you so shocked?
Perhaps the dust there is poisonous.
After what you've been through, what do you think?
Everything feels contrived.
Think about it.
The things I care about most
are my mates and my dogs.
Then, they vanished one by one
before my eyes.
Zhang Qishan cares about his men the most.
So, it took away Unit 401.
This tower is taking away the things everyone cares about the most.
Xiangu.
If it wants to torture you,
will it take me away?
Don't be so full of yourself.
It didn't take you away.
That means you are not the most important person to me.
It didn't take me away.
That means I'm also not
the one you care about most.
Nonsense.
That only means it doesn't know me well.
I've told you this.
If it dares hurt you, even by a little,
I'll fight it till it drops.
So, what is the most important thing
to you?
I don't know.
I hope this tower can tell me that.
No matter
what it is,
I'll protect it for you.
Master Zhang, look.
It's like this.
We came down to search for Unit 401.
Soon,
we found them.
They were
800 meters away from us.
However,
we couldn't catch up
no matter how hard we tried.
Until you
ordered
everyone to step back
and blasted a hole
in the floor,
we finally found them.
However, we realized
the unit
was controlled by a shadow.
So, you went to chase after the shadow.
Watch Unit 401!
Laogou and I
stayed behind to watch the unit.
But this unit
vanished before us
once again.
Where's Unit 401?
Next, Laogou's men also vanished.
So, we split up to look for them.
Then,
[Liunian Hall]
Liunian Hall
suddenly appeared in the corridor.
We went inside to find them
but we failed.
After that, we met you.
A shadow
controlled Unit 401?
Unit 401
arrived two days before us.
Why would they appear
and wait for us somewhere 800 meters away?
Right.
If they have been controlled by the shadow,
then the shadow was actually waiting for us.
I went to chase after the shadow.
You went to search for Laogou's men.
Why did we
end up in the same place?
Is this a coincidence?
I see it now.
This tower wants to lure us here.
If this tower wants to lure us here,
it just needs to use Unit 401.
Making Unit 401 vanish and appear again.
What's the point?
But Master Zhang,
monsters like this have no logic.
It probably thinks it's fun.
We are the toys.
It won't give up
until all of us are dead.
This tower is only 80 years old.
To put it bluntly,
it has a shorter lifespan than humans. How did it become a monster?
It must be working very hard.
So?
It works so hard just to fool around with us?
That doesn't seem right.
It lured me down here with Unit 401,
captured Wu Laogou's men,
and forced Laogou to enter deeper.
It knows both of us very well.
So, it must have done detailed research.
This is clearly a calculated plot.
Moreover, this person knows the Mystic Nine very well.
I think it's not just against a few of our clans.
Who is trying to harm the entire Mystic Nine?
[Changsha Garrison Command]
Commander,
Ding Qiansui invites you to meet at the Taihe Pleasure House.
I'm not going.
[Huo Wenhai, Changsha Special Commissioner]
A eunuch is asking you to meet him.
Someone like him
is trying to return to power
just because he thinks he is rich.
He is a useless remnant from the Qing Dynasty.
However, the messenger said something else.
Ding Qiansui
can help you get rid of Zhang Qishan.
Commander Huo,
there's no need to take this filth's words
seriously.
Ding Qiansui is indeed a scum,
but someone like him
is exactly the kind who knows how to survive in harsh conditions.
I'm a little interested in his schemes.
Come.
Let's go see what he's up to.
- I am wronged! - Mercy, please.
I am innocent!
Commander Huo, spare us!
We are innocent!
Have mercy!
- Commander Huo! - Commander Huo!
Commander Huo, spare us!
Commander Huo!
Everyone! Guns up!
Fire!
[Changsha Garrison Command]
I'm honored to have Commander Huo here.
Commander Huo is busy.
Make it quick.
Go out.
Commander Huo, come in and take a seat.
Now, spill it out.
Commander Huo.
How's your relationship
with Master Zhang?
Trying to sow discord?
Do you know I can execute you right now
according to military law?
However, I'll forget about this
since we are from the same hometown.
Commander Huo, stay.
I spoke out of turn just now.
However,
the news I heard
scares me.
What news?
Well,
you know
that the situation now is tense.
The Japanese are keeping a close eye on the situation.
Master Zhang,
as the Defense Commander of Changsha,
has achieved a lot
in defending the city over the years.
Everyone in the city...
Cut to the chase.
Yes.
A few days ago, I received a report from my scouts
saying that Master Zhang
has all these achievements
because the Japanese are involved.
Of course, I didn't believe it.
Master Zhang is the backbone of the Mystic Nine.
If what I heard was true, then...
Are you saying that Zhang Qishan is working with the Japanese?
Commander Huo,
I dare not say that.
If my scout has evidence,
then...
If what you say is true,
the Ministry of War will punish him accordingly.
However,
if you're just framing him for no reason,
the Ministry of War also won't forgive you for spreading rumors.
When the time comes,
you'll be punished.
When that happens,
I'll surely visit you and apologize to you in person.
Commander Huo,
calm down.
I know
you and Zhang Qishan are both in the Ministry of War
and have a strong bond.
When you hear the news,
you must find it hard to believe.
I get it.
If the news is true,
the Ministry of War must be angry.
My words carry little weight.
I can only rely on someone of your standing
to act as an intermediary.
The Ministry of War also needs someone
to take his spot.
Am I right?
[Zhang Qishan's Personal Information]
The war is reaching a critical point,
and you still need to deal with the Mystic Nine's sordid affairs?
Let's ignore this bunch of misfits.
I'm also a part of the Mystic Nine.
Am I also a part of the misfits?
No, Commander.
Sorry.
Forget it.
Saying that
means you don't understand the Mystic Nine.
Back then,
I could serve the Ministry of War
as someone from the Mystic Nine.
That means the Ministry of War
still values the people
from the Mystic Nine.
There must be a reason why the Mystic Nine has remained in Changsha
for so many years.
Why don't we work with the Mystic Nine?
I tried.
There's no use.
Each master of the Mystic Nine is highly skilled.
They are so arrogant
that they look down on each other.
Why would they take orders from someone else?
Only Zhang Qishan can make them obey him.
Changsha is a place
that looks calm on the surface
but is full of dangers
underneath.
Every clan of the Mystic Nine is on the same boat.
You don't need
to row faster than others,
but you need to keep this boat steady.
Some obey the law.
Some stand on the front line.
Some are well-versed in worldly matters.
Some are ambitious.
We need everyone.
That is how
we can hold
the fate of the situation in our hands.
The Ministry of War isn't afraid of the Mystic Nine.
However, the same cannot be said about the people
in the Ministry of War.
Today, you rise.
Tomorrow, I fall.
Everyone is trying to undermine each other.
Everyone
has asked the Mystic Nine for help.
Naturally, the Mystic Nine
has dirt on everyone in their hands.
If they offend the Mystic Nine,
all their secrets might be leaked one day.
Doing that is no different from giving their enemies leverage.
[Eryue Hong's Personal Information]
Eryue Hong.
[Pear Garden]
The Hong Clan manages the city's grain transport.
Their men are spread across all waterways.
Eryue Hong's skill
is being elusive.
He can escape from anywhere.
With this skill of his,
he is also graceful and captivating on the stage.
He is the most famous opera actor
in the Changsha Flower Drum Opera Troupe.
Whenever he sings,
the place will be full.
[Eryue Hong, Hong Clan of Mystic Nine]
Although Eryue Hong left the Mystic Nine
after his wife's death,
his reputation and assets still exist.
Eryue Hong
is the most unfathomable
and hardest to deal with.
If Zhang Qishan were dead,
the news could stay hidden for a few days.
But if a famous figure like him were to die,
all of Changsha
and even the whole country would be shocked within half a day.
Then, Mystic Nine will be alert.
It'll be even harder
to take them down one by one.
Banjie Li.
[Banjie Li's Personal Information]
This guy just won't die.
Third Master.
Both his legs were broken by his partners when he was young.
He was trapped in the ditch for a week,
[Banjie Li, Li Clan of Mystic Nine]
- Third Master. - surviving on muddy water.
Wait.
He is the most ruthless person in Mystic Nine.
He is very suspicious.
- Thank you, Third Master.
- Rumor has it
- Let me help you.
- that he sleeps in a tomb every night
because he doesn't trust the living.
Third Master.
- Third Master.
- He manages the lowest class here.
- Almost all the beggars
- Thank you, Third Master.
- and the disabled rely on him to live.
He has spies at every corner.
Let's go take a look.
If Banjie Li is killed,
the people will cause trouble in the streets.
When the government can't handle it,
it'll still affect the Ministry of War.
Fourth Master.
[Fourth Master's Personal Information]
This man
used to study under Eryue Hong.
Later, he betrayed him and was chased out.
Not only can he use iron pellets,
but the nine-claw hook he created
can also kill easily.
He is the most inhumane one
among the Mystic Nine.
There's no right and wrong to him.
He only does what he likes best
[Chen Pi Asi, Fourth Master of Mystic Nine]
without considering the consequences.
Whether you are a high-ranking official,
or a foreign dignitary,
if you offend him,
he will try to kill you
even if it costs his life.
You must make sure you kill him in one attempt.
Otherwise, you'll be in deep trouble in the future.
Laogou.
[Wu Laogou's Personal Information]
He is the only crack in Mystic Nine.
He hasn't joined Mystic Nine for long,
but he hates Zhang Qishan a lot.
He is decisive in killing
and great at scheming.
Most importantly, he holds grudges easily.
His blade
is already pointing at Zhang Qishan.
[Heibei Laoliu, Sixth Master of Mystic Nine]
Laoliu was a swordsman of Shaanxi.
He likes to act alone.
It's possible
to kill him,
but his swordsmanship is impeccable.
He can kill someone in one strike.
Many people
wanted to kill him and take over his position over the years,
but none has succeeded.
[Huo Xiangu's Personal Information]
Xiangu.
She's from my family.
I still want to protect her, if possible.
Of course,
if Huo Xiangu has a backbone,
let her die together with the Huo clan.
However, if she insists on going her own way,
I don't think the women of my family
would listen to her.
[Qi Tiezui's Personal Information]
Tiezui.
He knows everything in the world.
When I wanted to kill him,
he left Changsha immediately.
[Masterful Divination]
I didn't know how he found out.
However, his skills
are by no means ordinary.
[Xie Jiu]
Jiu.
He is close to every faction.
He's troublesome.
I need to keep him in check first.
Otherwise,
this whole thing will get complicated.
However, I can't do anything to him directly.
He has many business dealings
with the high-ranking officials in the Ministry of War.
I can't afford to offend any of them.
It's Runty's collar.
Master, it's safe.
Get ready to depart.
Did your turtle
get eaten by the monster
and the monster is now plucking the rope?
The monster doesn't know the Zhang Clan's secret code.
Tiezui.
Master Zhang.
Are you coming with us or are you staying?
Of course, I'm following.
You've changed.
When the Mystic Nine was formed,
I swore to go through everything together.
I'm eighth in the Mystic Nine.
How can I be a coward
at a time like this?
Did you do a divination behind our backs?
Nonsense. I'm being a good friend now.
Get ready.
We'll leave in five minutes.
- Yes! - Yes!
Master Zhang.
Are you there, Master Zhang?
Laogou.
Are you there, Laogou?
Master Zhang.
Master Zhang, are you there?
Say something.
Are you there?
Laogou.
All right.
I'm glad that we're all here.
Let's have a chat.
It's rare
for the three all-rounder clans to gather.
We are
good at literary arts, martial arts,
and even scheming.
It's the ultimate combination.
Shut up.
Why are there so many skulls here?
Obviously, they buried humans in the foundation
when they built this.
The bones are still intact,
and the joints have not come apart.
This doesn't look like natural decomposition.
Xiaojin, bring one along.
Yes.
I didn't find them.
But I found this.
Runty.
Runty!
- Tianpeng! - Zhenyuan!
Tianpeng!
Zhenyuan!
- Zhenyuan! - Master Zhang.
I've investigated this place.
This is a completely sealed space.
I'm sure they were here,
but they vanished somehow.
There's something sinister about this place.
Master Zhang.
I brought the skull.
Did you see anything strange
at the waterway just now?
Are you talking about the skulls?
That shouldn't be surprising to you.
Did you see something else?
Forget it.
I probably made a mistake.
You'd never make a mistake.
Let me tell you honestly.
This place is eerie.
The smaller the details, the more important they are.
Just tell me.
Otherwise, you'd feel like
there's a weight in your heart.
You think I don't care about you,
right?
Tell me.
Just now, near the skulls,
I saw a very strange window.
Someone was standing inside.
That man
looked a lot like the Otherworld Patriarch.
If he dares to harm you,
I chop him up
and mix him with the foundation of the building.
You don't need to worry about me.
I will protect myself.
Did you notice anything?
This hand comes out from the mouth.
This head comes out from the stomach.
All these body parts
are mixed together.
They are not from this world.
Master Zhang.
This hand isn't a broken limb.
It has flesh on it
and goes deep into the abdominal cavity.
Moreover, this body didn't have external injuries.
It doesn't seem like it has been planted from the outside.
It's like the hand grew from inside the body.
Check all bodies.
If it's manmade,
there will be an indicator.
Yes.
Fifth Master,
we investigated everything.
This place is completely sealed.
Fifth Master.
This hall
is exactly the same as the previous one,
but this one is a lot older.
As in?
Is it one year older or a decade older?
Give me a number.
Fifth Master,
this brick is a mix of old lime, clay, and sand.
Gray nails are used between the cracks.
No stone powder is added.
They are built through grouting of dry joints.
A technique like this
is from either the early Ming dynasty or the late Yuan Dynasty.
Where are
Tianpeng and the rest, then?
The building outside is new,
but this building is old?
Oh, no.
I see it now.
What's going on?
I...
I just wanted
to make a divination, and the jade pendant fell.
Master Zhang.
I know what's going on
but I dare not say it.
Don't be afraid.
I am here.
A ritual took place here.
It's called the Three Primes Sun-Moon Great Peace Fasting Rite.
Tiezui,
remember to be concise.
All right.
Sure.
This ritual
was used to open
the gates to Heaven.
A gate will be opened here
that goes directly to Heaven.
However, a problem seemed to have happened.
The cause of the problem
is probably the symbol on this flag.
The symbol on it
has been changed into the symbol of a cult.
A cult?
The ritual failed
and all of them died.
Stop spouting nonsense here.
A failed ritual
will never kill.
Laogou.
This spell opens a gate to Heaven.
If the flag is wrong,
the gate
probably doesn't lead to Heaven, first of all.
Second,
where the door leads to
is unknown.
Although they didn't go to Heaven,
the Otherworld Patriarch proved that he could use spells.
He just didn't excel in it.
He has achieved his goal, more or less.
It is all fake.
The only objective of the Otherworld Tower
is to let the followers believe
that spells truly exist.
Throughout history, all this talk of spirits and the supernatural
has been used to deceive the world.
I, Zhang Qishan, swear with my life,
that everything here is a lie.
Tiezui,
if you have more proof to convince me,
show me.
If you can't,
I'll crush this place.
Master Zhang, I...
Yes, Master Zhang.
I'll surely find evidence for you.
Over there.
Only a hand and a head
passed through
and the passage was closed.
The hand and head
were severed in the bodies of these followers.
But look at this body.
It is complete
with the mouth open.
However, there's nothing inside.
That means
at least,
something made its way here successfully.
It must be the shadow you chased after.
The shadow was here for a long time?
The ritual was carried out years ago,
but it only harms people recently?
What has the shadow been doing all this time?
How would I know?
Perhaps the shadow
was still young when it just came here.
It has only become an adult recently.
Whether it's a human
or a spirit,
regardless of its objective
or what it wants us to do,
I will never let it get its wish.
Master Qiansui.
The building...
The building is shaking.
Don't be afraid.
The more it shakes, the more it feels comfortable.
Master.
The unions and farewells of life are impossible to foresee.
Let us watch the splendid play that unfolds this day.
Help
dig the waterway.
- Yes! - Yes!
Don't move.
It might collapse again.
Master Zhang.
This is a common deep rock fracture.
The layers underneath have been flattened.
This road is definitely blocked.
I get it now!
We are trapped here forever.
Speak.
We are trapped here.
The only waterway
has collapsed.
We can't leave.
The only way to leave this place
is to carry out the Three Primes Sun-Moon Great Peace Fasting Rite
to connect to the other world.
Then, there might still be a chance.
Otherworld Patriarch.
No.
You are probably the shadow.
Come out.
I know you're here.
You used Unit 401
to lure us here
because you want us to carry out the ritual to send you home.
No need.
Unit 401 was already here.
Just let them carry out the ritual.
Wu Laogou,
don't run your mouth.
Besides,
my dogs are not required for the ritual.
Return my dogs first.
All of you don't believe me.
All of you are looking down on me.
Why don't we follow Tiezui's method first?
The people of the Wu Clan should do it first.
We'll take responsibility if all of you die.
Ridiculous!
It'll take three years
for you to learn the spell now.
Don't underestimate my expertise.
It's not that easy.
Take him away.
Dream on.
Tiezui has gone mad.
What do you think, Master Zhang?
You don't believe in the supernatural.
Carrying out a ritual is probably
beneath you.
Let me do it on your behalf.
No need. We'll do it together.
Just don't tell anyone after we escape.
Everyone,
prepare for the ritual.
Help Tiezui get changed.
Everyone, pay attention to Tiezui's steps and rhythm.
If the tower
is hinting at us to carry out this ritual,
while Tiezui is carrying out the ritual,
his feet might step on some traps
that create illusions.
That's all?
That's all.
Where's the gate?
Where is it?
The gate...
Master,
there's nothing inside.
- Master! - Master!
Master!
The gate has indeed opened.
Zhang Qishan did go there.
Why wasn't there any sound?
Tiezui.
Help me do another ritual.
No, Fifth Master.
Exactly. Even Master Zhang is gone.
Since Zhang Qishan went there,
Tianpeng and the rest
might have gone there too.
I must take a look.
Otherwise, the Wu Clan
will be looked down upon by the Zhang Clan.
We promised to help them find Unit 401.
In the end, we failed
and Zhang Qishan has gone missing.
Even if we can return alive,
I'll be too embarrassed to stay in Changsha.
What nonsense ritual.
Let me experience it.
Everyone, be on standby here.
If I find something,
I'll try to send a message back here.
Tiezui, carry out the ritual.
If I don't return,
follow Tiezui's orders for civilian matters.
For matters about wars and fights,
follow Madam Huo's orders.
Come on.
Tiezui, please carry out the ritual.
- Laogou. - Enough.
Hurry.
Laogou.
- Fifth Master! - Fifth Master!
- Laogou! - Fifth Master!
Fifth Master!
♪The past fades like smoke♪
♪A choice is made in silence♪
♪In this labyrinthine puzzle♪
♪Who can reach the shore?♪
♪Just an ordinary farewell♪
♪The sun seems to shine bright over our heads♪
♪But this could be our last trip together♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Take care♪
♪We once raced♪
♪For the dawn♪
♪Ever-lasting bond, a satisfying vindication♪
♪In the web of fate♪
♪No one can escape♪
♪Life and death cut like a blade♪
♪We too were young once♪
♪Fortunate to brave the raging waves together♪
♪Keep the ember lit♪
♪To illuminate the journey ahead♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Please, do take care of yourself♪